Pray for forgiveness.
The Nun is a horror film directed by Corin Hardy.
A priest with a dark past and a novice nearing her final vows are sent by the
Vatican to Romania to investigate a nun's death and face a demonic force.
Sister Irene, played by Taissa Farmiga.
Father Burke, played by Demián Bichir.
The Nun / Valak, played by Bonnie Aarons.
Maurice Theriault, played by Jonas Bloquet.
Sister Oana, played by Ingrid Bisu.
Ed Warren, played by Patrick Wilson.
The Nun is a 2018 American gothic supernatural horror film directed by Corin Hardy and
written by Gary Dauberman, from a story by Dauberman and James Wan.
It serves as a spiritual spin-off to The Conjuring 2 and is the
fifth installment in The Conjuring shared universe.
The film stars Taissa Farmiga, Demián Bichir and Jonas Bloquet, with Bonnie Aarons reprising
her role as the Demon Nun, an incarnation of Valak, from The Conjuring 2.
The plot follows a Roman Catholic priest and a nun in her novitiate
as they uncover an unholy secret in 1952 Romania.
It has a sequel, The Nun II, released in 2023.
Warner Bros.
Pictures and New Line Cinema announced The Nun, a spin-off film to The Conjuring 2,
which had opened five days earlier, with Peter Safran and Wan producing.
The film's initial script was by David Leslie Johnson.
Hardy had signed on to direct The Nun with a new
screenplay by Wan and Dauberman.
Principal photography began in May 2017 in Bucharest, Romania.
The Nun was released in the United States on September 7, 2018.
It received mixed reviews and grossed $366 million worldwide off a $22 million budget, becoming
the highest-grossing film of the Conjuring series at the time of its release.
In 2023, a better-received sequel, The Nun II, was released.
The film explores themes of rome, italy, nun, supernatural, exorcism, halloween.
The tone is dark.